ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
木浅
时间轴
念念  今
电脑狂人
第四季
第四集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
如果你住这里  就已经到家了
六周后
彗星
两个月后
燃烧激情
彗星
丰富植被
考特妮情人
燃烧激情
锅贴
窈窕奶爸
吃瘪吧
平绒圆顶小帽
金滑板奖
流浪者
一个月后
感觉还是很乱
It still feels random.
我搜了"达拉斯+牛仔队"
I searched "Dallas plus Cowboys,"
第一个好像是个烂大联盟粉丝网站
I'm sure the first hit is a crappy NFL fan site,
但是第二条搜索结果是什么鬼
but the second site that comes up?
没准流浪者知道你
Yeah, well, maybe Rover knows
压根不看橄榄球
you don't give a shit about football?
我忘了你在加大时是全美跑锋了
Yeah, I forgot you were an all-American running back at Cal.
我就去看过一场球
I went to a game once.
我只是说  流浪者在关联性上有问题
I'm just saying, Rover has a relevance problem.
-山达基教是宗教还是邪教  -邪教
- Is Scientology a religion or a cult? - Cult.
他们十月就申请到了非营利组织地位了
They obtained non-profit status in October.
算了  我自己想想往哪归类吧
Never mind, I'll figure out where it goes.
这些结果顶多只能说一般般
These results are mediocre at best.
流浪者"天才"搜索引擎最终得分  C-
Final grade for Rover's "genius" search engine, C-.
我看是D-
D-.
非得这么烧吗
Is that really necessary?
听动静不太对啊
That doesn't sound right.
-听起来油管好像...  -我能行
- Sounds like the, uh, gas line is... - I got it!
好吧
Okay.
反正我又不是从小就在修车店里打滚
Not like I literally grew up in an auto shop or anything.
等雨停了她就走
It's just until the rain stops.
吵得我心都乱了
Well, I can't hear myself think.
听着  如果他们调整好了关联性问题
Listen, if they fix the relevance problem,
那我们可能就有竞争对手了
we could have a competition on our hands.
要不再搜索一下...
You know, hit search for, um...
是流浪者吗
Is that Rover?
我们评分为C-
We give it a C-.
这么烂
That bad?
你真没用过吗
You really haven't seen it?
我还真没用过
No, I really haven't.
等等
Wait, uh...
我明白你什么意思了
Yeah. I see what you mean.
即使有基本规则引擎
Even with the basic rules engine,
结果还是太烂  网络爬虫太呆了
the results are garbage, the crawler's too static.
不过他们抓取网站标题的方法还挺聪明的
Still, the way they grabbed the titles is actually kind of clever.
-多谢你的意见  -再让我看看网站代码
- Okay, thanks for this... - Hey, I'm just gonna check the HTML,
就一小会儿
it takes one second.
好吧
Oh, yeah.
算法无法识别
The algorithm's too stupid to know
搜索关键词中的相关同义词
that there are equivalent synonyms for a search phrase,
或者不同的拼写
or different spellings.
比如美式拼写"颜色"
Like "color, c-o-l-o-r,"
就比英式拼写少一个字母"U"
the English spelling, with a "U."
不过我还是打个B-
Still, I'd give it a B-.
真的  概念绝对值个B
No, a solid B for concept,
但是执行太差  是个减分项
but demerits for poor execution.
你问的
You asked.
-其实我们没问  -我们根本没问
- Actually, we didn't. - No, we didn't.
谁都没开口
Neither one of us asked.
打败他们根本不难  知道吗
This wouldn't be hard to beat, you know?
只需要想出一种更精准的算法
You just have to come up with a more sophisticated algorithm.
这不是我们的思路
That's not really our approach.
人们需要更有组织的列表
People need a curated list,
需要一个指引他们在网络迷宫中行走的向导
a guide through the disorganized maze of the web...
而不是一堆不通人情的算法
not a bunch of impersonal math.
首先  我觉得算数很有人性
First of all, math is very personal to me.
-当然  我只是说  -其次
- Of course. I just mean that... - And second,
五百个网站你们组织起来容易
curation is fine if you guys have 500 websites,
或者五千个
or 5000.
但等有五百万个网站了  你们怎么办
But what are you guys gonna do when you have 5 million?
你们打算怎么引导用户应付那么多
How are you gonna guide people through that?
那我们就告诉你哪个网站最好
We tell you which site is best.
整个公司就是建立在人工处理的基础上
The whole company is built around a human approach.
-黄片警报  -来了  我来了
- Porn alert. - Yep. Yep. Coming.
根据公司规定
Following company protocol
-我将立即离开电脑  -我来了  来了
- and stepping away from the machine. - Coming. Coming.
-你生气了  -我没有
- You're mad. - I'm not.
-真没有  -我还以为你不想参与进来
- I'm not. - I didn't think you wanted to work on this,
但如果你想的话
but if you do, then...
-我不想  -好吧
- I don't. - Okay.
我只是想说
I'm j... I'm just saying that
算法没办法区分质量上的好坏
math can't tell a qualitative difference between good and bad.
电脑不能告诉我我想要什么
A computer can't tell me what I want.
现在还不能
Not yet.
好吧
Okay.
我们的功能还有问题
We have functionality issues.
用户的搜索结果前几条都不对
Users aren't getting something useful as their first return,
所以他们就不用了
so they're leaving the site.
说实话  我们上线太早了
Frankly, we launched too early...
我们有彗星这个强劲的竞争对手
We had a major competitor in Comet...
好吧  先别把事情都扯到彗星上去
Okay, let's try not to make this all about Comet.
-还要考虑到整个市场...  -没错
- There's the larger landscape of... - Exactly.
我们需要有存在感
We needed to get out there to have a presence.
彗星不是我们的竞争对手
Comet isn't competitive...
-我刚说什么来着  -抱歉
- What did I just say? - Sorry.
看来我们太心急了
It seems like we were impatient.
并不是  上线运行是好事
No. No. No, it's good that we're live.
真的
It is.
访问量早晚会起来的
The growth will be there.
流浪者的算法会越用越好的
The Rover algorithm's gonna get better with usage.
我们需要用户的访问足迹
We needed users to track,
更多数据会帮我们改进算法的
the data is gonna help us refine this algorithm.
我们必须得保持竞争力
We've got to stay competitive...
我告诉你  我们比彗星有优势
I'm telling you, we have a leg up on Comet...
-你说什么  -索引网站
- Excuse me. - Index sites.
谢谢
Thank you.
只要我们对我们的系统有信心
If we could just have faith in our system...
我当然有信心
Hey, I do have faith.
所以我才让网站上线了
That's why I launched the damn thing.
网站已经上线了
The site is live,
所以是否过早的问题已经没意义了
so the question of timing is a moot point.
求你们别跑来当着我的面吵架
Please don't come in here and argue at me.
-我手上的事太多了  -好吧
- I've got a lot of other things on my plate. - All right.
你们要是没统一意见
How can you lead this effectively
还怎么有效领导整个项目呢
if you're not speaking the same language?
商量好
Pull it together.
-谢谢  -明白
- Thank you. - Copy that.
眼下搜索市场正在跑马圈地
Search is a land grab, right now.
只要这块地盘圈住了
And once we grab all the land,
我们就能考虑加入更多代码了
then we can think about incorporating more code.
卡梅说得对
Cam's got a point.
目前的模型不能规模化
The current model isn't scalable.
我们三个人是跟不上网络扩张的
The three of us can't keep up with the expansion.
但我们不该加入更多代码
But we shouldn't add more code.
-而是该加入更多人  -多少人
- We should add more people. - How many?
总不能给所有人发糖果当工资吧
I mean, we can't pay everybody in Necco Wafers.
雇一个工程师是一回事
You know, hiring an engineer is one thing...
我们最强的版块是哪个
What's our strongest section?
-大概是喜剧  -没错
- Probably comedy. - Exactly.
海莉喜欢看喜剧
Haley loves comedy,
所以这个版块最全面  最有条理
so it's out most thorough, well-organized section.
那我们需要的就是专家
Well, then, we need experts.
就是那种
You know, someone...
那种痴迷于...
someone who's obsessed with like...
-运动  -运动的人
- Sports. - ...sports.
没错
Exactly.
我们需要更多的海莉
We need more Haleys.
可恶
Damn it!
对  获得图书馆学博士学位最酷的一点
Yeah, the... the best thing a-about a PhD in Library Science
就是我可以自称"图书馆学博士"
is I get to call myself a "Bibliothecographer."
你是芝加哥艺术馆的照片归档员
So you were a photography archivist at Chicago Art Institute.
听起来很厉害
Th-That sounds cool.
其实那里太冷
Hypothermic, actually,
我只待了一个冬天
I survived exactly one winter.
我是加州姑娘
I'm a California girl.
但不是大卫·李·罗斯那种风格的
But not in the David Lee Roth kind of way.
你能举例说明你的工作方法吗
Can you, uh... can you give us an example of your methodology?
比如说
For instance,
你怎么整理你的唱片
how do you organize your CDs?
这个嘛  我
Well, my, um...
我弟弟很喜欢重金属
my brother is really into metal,
所以我帮他整理唱片库
and I helped him manage his collection.
我把所有的死亡金属唱片放在一个架子上
I put all of the death metal CDs on one shelf,
死亡讣告和食人尸这类乐队
from the simple bands like Obituary and Cannibal Corpse
放最左  然后旋死和技术死放中间
on the left, to melodic and technical death in the middle,
然后是死亡/黑金
followed by death/black
碾核/死亡等交叉风格
and grind/death and death crossovers,
然后我把工业死
and then I put the industrial death,
民谣死和几乎不算死之类的放在最后
folk death, and barely-death, uh, at the end.
然后  另一个架子专门放黑金属
And... And then, the next shelf was for black metal,
从挪威黑金属
through the whole Norwegian scene,
像Mayhem和Burzum
like Mayhem and Burzum,
再到不黑
through the un-black
再到其实不黑但风格挺像黑的那种
and then the not-really-black-but-sorta-fits,
比如恶灵天皇
like Cradle of Filth.
另外还有
And... Oh, do...
要我继续说下去吗
do you want me to keep going?
还有邋遢力量
The-There's Raunchy Power...
不  已经很好了
No, that's perfect.
-邋遢力量  -一般人只是按首字母排列
- Raunchy Power? - Most people just alphabetize.
你确定是你弟弟的唱片库吗
You sure this was your brother's collection?
好吧  最后一个问题
Okay, one final thing...
一个关于"barks"[多义词]的网站
How would you list a website
你怎么归类
about "barks"?
看你是什么意思了  是狗吠  树皮
Depends if you mean dog noise, tree layer,
还是根汁汽水  拼写不太一样
root beer... that's Barq's with a "Q"...
还是船
or boat.
等等  还有船的意思吗
Wait. "B-Bark" Is a boat?
严格来讲是一种三桅帆船[barque]
technically, it's a sailing ship with three or more masts.
我们都不知道自己出的难题的答案
We don't even know the answer to our own trick question.
凯蒂·赫曼博士  你被录用了
Dr. Katie Herman, you are officially hired
你是彗星的首席本体论专家
as Comet's Chief Ontologist.
完美
Perfect.
来给你介绍一下各种"迷"吧
Let's introduce you to the obsessives.
或者  我们喊他们
Or, as we like to call them...
冲浪者
the surfers.
我们每天都能收到上百封邮件
Every day, we receive hundreds of e-mails
要求我们把他们的网站加入索引
from people asking us to add their websites to our index.
而且  我们也在不停地寻找
Plus, we're constantly on the look-out
新网站加入分类
for new sites to catalogue.
当冲浪者找到一个网站  会把网站分类
When a surfer finds a site, they categorize it
加入彗星网的总列表
and add it to Comet's master list.
每个小组都要添加索引条目
Each group is responsible for growing the index
并为每一门类下前五的网站写简介
and writing descriptions for the top five sites in each category.
是的  但问题是
Yeah, but the problem is,
我们一开始只有五大主题
is that we started out with five main topics.
随着新网站出现
As new sites pop up, you know,
给他们分类变得越来越复杂
categorizing them becomes more and more...complicated.
-本体论中有一个专门的术语  -一团乱
- Yeah, there's an ontological term for that. - Yeah -- "Shit-show."
好吧  先介绍一下娱乐
All right, let's start with Entertainment.
这是视频的雷吉
This is Reggie from Le Video --
他凭他对法国新浪潮
He, uh, impressed Joe
和约翰·坎迪的如数家珍
with his vast knowledge of French New Wave
-折服了乔  -是的
- as well as the canon of John Candy. - Yeah.
你知道他饰演过克里夫·默多克吗
Did you know that he played Cliff Murdoch,
《年度新秀奖》里的主持人
the Announcer in "Rookie of the Year"
-没被列入演职员表  -真的吗
- uncredited? - Really?
-是的  -厉害
- Yeah. - That's amazing.
-太酷了  雷吉  -回见了
- Really cool, Reggie. - Take care, all right?
-你看  热情让他们情绪高涨  -嗯
- See, enthusiasm feeds them. - Yeah.
这两位是洛林和波
So this is Lorraine and Po,
分别来自淘儿唱片和城市之光
from Tower Records and City Lights, respectively.
你们的喜剧达人呢
Where is your comedy geek?
-那个板块棒极了  -选得好
- That section rocks. - Good choice.
那其实是我女儿  海莉
That is actually my daughter Haley,
她也是我们的成员  她不上学的时候来
who's part of the team. When she's not at school.
-本地网站在这边  -好的
- And regional's over here. - Okay.
需要餐厅推荐的话
You need a restaurant recommendation?
找这几个小伙儿准没错
These are your guys.
不光是小伙儿啊
Not just guys.
瑞莎  我们在公交车上认识的
Risa. We met on a bus.
她发了一个餐厅排名列表
She launched into a list of restaurant ratings
能让扎格调查自惭形秽
that would put Zagat's to shame.
顺便一提  查格调查出了新网站
FYI, Zagat's has a new website,
但被商务队抢去了
but the Biz team scooped us --
查格调查是大企业
Zagat's is big business,
是国际的  不是本地的
it's international, not regional.
那是金牌健身俱乐部的麦基
That's Macky from Gold's Gym.
你不会相信的  但他有工商管理学硕士学位
You wouldn't believe it, but this guy's got an MBA.
市场部老大
Marketing honcho.
是我让金牌开网站的
I told Gold's to launch a website --
当他们终于采纳了这建议
And when they finally did --
我们就从本地手里抢走了它
we scooped it up from regional.
-各位  -你们可以互相引用
- Guys. - Well, you could cross-reference it.
没错  就这样  你理解我们的窘境了
Yes. Do that. So, you see our quandary.
商业  体育
Business, Sports...
-理解  -这是我们的首席程序员泰德
- I'm with ya. - This is our head coder. Ted.
整个网站都是他管理的
He manages the whole site for us.
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to interrupt,
美国在线的麦克·豪斯曼找你
you have a call from Michael Houseman at AOL.
完美  你可以随意...
Perfect. Feel free to, uh...
-我可以  明白  -发挥特长
- I'm just -- Yeah, I got it... - work your magic.
交给我了  好的
I got it covered, yeah.
-麦克  -麦克  我是戈登
- Mike. - Mike, it's Gordon.
如果你来电是为卡奈特的事骂我
If you're calling to bust my balls about CalNect,
那可来不及了
you're a little bit late,
它早已被遗忘了
they've already been busted into oblivion.
真遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
我是想跟你说  美国在线在考虑开发搜索
I wanted to let you know -- AOL is in the market for a search play.
继续说
We're listening.
老实说  你们彗星的成就
Frankly, we're impressed by what you've got going on
让人佩服
over there at Comet.
巧妙  简练
Smart, lean.
我不想冒犯
I don't want to be too forward,
不过你们对收购有意向吗
but are you guys entertaining acquisition offers?
天哪  他们添加了简介
God, they've added editorial descriptions.
老天爷啊  好快
Jeez Louise, that was fast...
他们的算法是怎么做的
How're they doing their algorithm?
不是算法  是人做的
It's not an algorithm, it's people.
我们为什么不行
Well, why can't we do that?
给我首轮融资
Give me Series A,
我就雇四十个写手写广告
I'll hire 40 grunts to write blurbs.
我们还没到首轮融资的时候
We're not ready for Series A.
不要着急
Don't jump the gun.
你确定还要喝吗
You sure you need more of that?
我就靠这个活了
It's the only thing keeping me alive.
我们的网站和唐娜前夫的彗星
Isn't it a weird coincidence that we launched
在同一时间发布  你不觉得太巧了吗
just as Donna's ex-husband unveiled Comet?
大家都在搞搜索
Search was in the ether.
我们都不知道他们现在关系如何
We don't even know how much they talk to each other.
感觉她对整件事都很别扭
She just seems tweaked about the whole thing,
如坐针毡
like she's got a bug up her ass.
好了
All right.
告诉我最新进展  具体点
Give me the update. I want specifics.
维拉正在研究自然语言查询
Vera's been working on natural language queries,
试图让电脑理解
trying to make the computer understand
人类的提问方式
how humans ask questions.
我们只有一个程序员
We only have one coder.
西塞尔是顶尖的  但他工作量太大
Cecil's the best -- but he's overworked.
-艾略特  -伙计  这是事实  不是你的错
- Elliot-- - Dude, it's true. It's not your fault.
但如果能给他找些帮手
But if we could get him some help --
基本上  他在试图改善搜索算法
He's essentially trying to refine the search algorithm
并改进网络爬虫
and improve the crawler.
他无法同时做这两件事
He can't do both simultaneously.
选一下你想让我先解决哪个致命问题吧
Pick which horrible problem you want me to attack first.
事实上  我们是应该添一些人手
Yeah, hey, the truth is, we could use a few more bodies.
这位可以负责重头部分
Our man here can do the heavy lifting,
但他也需要一些支持
but he's gonna need some support.
-我们需要的是首轮融资  -艾略特
- What we need is Series A-- - Elliot --
你们近期内是拿不到首轮融资的
You guys are not getting a Series A term sheet anytime soon.
这正是我想要的
This is exactly what I was hoping for!
我朋友托丽·洛曼有一辆清风房车
My friend Tori Lowman had an Airstream,
我们以前在里面玩
we used to play in it.
是吗
Yeah?
你们都玩什么
What would you play?
清风啊
Airstream.
所以你们在计划越野旅行吗
So you're planning on a cross-country trip?
没有  我刚买了块地
No, I just bought a-a piece of land,
我需要先找个地方住
and I need something over my head
再去搭建更长久的建筑
before I build something more permanent.
是吗  哪里的地
Yeah? Where's the land?
-就在邦尼顿西边  -那里超美的
- Just west of Bonny Doon. - Ooh, that's so pretty.
-我懂  -是啊
- I know. - Yeah.
我丈夫伦尼和我
Well, my husband, Lenny, and I,
我们买了这辆好家伙去度蜜月
we bought this old sweetheart for our honeymoon.
它可是个宝
And, uh, she's a real jewel.
你们多久去一次那里
So, how often do you get up there?
我们才去了一次
We've only been once.
-但我们希望多去去那里  -没错
- But we're hoping to make it more often. - Yeah.
挺好
Okay.
去吧
Well, go on.
进去看看  里面非常舒适
Go on inside. It's nice and cozy.
床睡着也很舒服
And the bed's pretty comfortable, too.
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
简直完美
This is perfect!
这很...
It's...
很"舒适"
It's "cozy."
好吧
Yeah.
那么  美国在线
So...AOL, huh?
是啊
Yeah.
你真的还想再当个公司职员
You really ready to be a company man again?
如果价格够高的话
If the money -- money's good enough,
我可能会接受收购
I might take the buy-out.
去做点别的
Do something else.
-你可能会  -是啊
- You might. - Yeah.
莉迪娅让我们试试床
Lydia said to try it out...
那我们就试试
so let's try it out.
答应我
Promise me that,
无论报价如何  你都要考虑一下
whatever the offer is, you'll consider it.
我甚至觉得你应该接受
I kinda think you should take it.
因为我们的商业模式无法规模化吗
Because our business model won't scale?
-什么  -不是
- What? - No.
因为...
Because...
那样你就可以把所有空余时间都用来陪我了
then you can spend all that free time with me.
另外  我知道你最看重人"攻"了
Besides, I know you're all about the human touch.
这辆"蜜月花车"意味着你要搬出去了吗
Does this "Long, long trailer" mean you're moving out?
1953年美国喜剧电影
不
No.
这是给我们的
This is for us.
我们有这么多空间来...
We'll have all this room to just...
随心所欲
do whatever we want.
-我知道我想做什么  -我们该停下了
- I know what I want to do. - Okay, let's stop.
好吧  莉迪娅
All right, Lydia.
这么多年来她和伦尼都住下来了
And it worked for her and Lenny for all these years.
你是想让我像伦尼那样安顿下来吗
Are you trying to make an honest Lenny out of me?
我是想买下这车
I am trying to buy this, here,
这个宝
jewel...
然后带你进入梦幻之境
and sweep you away to a magical land.
我去给报价
I'm gonna make an offer.
妈妈  我们还去吗
Mom...? Are we going?
妈
Mom?
你不像是准备好了
You don't look ready.
我知道  亲爱的
I know, baby.
我
I just --
我不知道我今晚能不能出去了
I don't know if I'm up for it tonight.
-但你喜欢女生外出之夜的  -我是喜欢
- But you love girls' night out. - I do love it.
我就是觉得或许
I just thought maybe
我们这次可以在家里度过
we could have girls' night in this time?
是因为工作吗
Is it work?
我知道谈这事很怪
I know it's weird to talk about it.
没有  亲爱的  我们想聊什么都行的
No, honey. We can talk about whatever you want.
而且  是啊
And, yeah,
我们是有些问题
we've been having some trouble.
流浪者吗
With Rover?
它肯定会很赞的
Well, I'm sure it'll be awesome.
卡梅说她很喜欢的
I mean, Cam said she liked it.
卡梅伦什么时候说她喜欢流浪者了
When did Cameron say she liked Rover?
我不知道  几个月前吧
I don't know, like a couple months ago?
她说那个算法挺"聪明"
She said the algorithm was "clever."
知道什么才聪明吗
You know what's really clever
是你的理查德·普赖尔简介
is your Richard Pryor blurb.
谢谢
Thanks.
事实上  亲爱的  我们被你打得好惨
The truth is, baby, you are kicking our ass.
是啊
Well, you're right,
工作好累人
work is just so exhausting.
我们该放松一下
So, we should just relax.
是啊
Yes.
我们叫外卖吧
How about we order take-out?
好啊  我们能叫中餐吗
Oh, yeah, can we get Chinese?
-好啊  -我好喜欢锅贴
- Yeah. - I love potstickers!
你怎么穿着那个
Why are you wearing that?
我们要叫中餐外卖
We're gonna order Chinese food.
恶心
Hella gross.
味精会让我发胖
MSG makes me bloat,
叫披萨吧
just order pizza.
琼妮  你妹妹在看卡通呢
Joanie! Your sister was watching cartoons --
妈妈  天呐  那不是卡通
Mom, Jesus, it's not just cartoons --
她不介意的  是吧
She doesn't mind. Right?
嗯
Yeah.
看你想看的吧  叫披萨也行
Watch whatever you want. And pizza's fine.
不  亲爱的  锅贴呢
No, well, honey, what about, you know, potstickers?
我也没那么饿
I'm actually not that hungry.
卡梅伦"拖车"
Cameron "Howe-to" --
去吧
Go! Go!
我没懂笑点
I don't get it.
是不太好
Well, it's not one of my best.
酷啊
Cool.
真漂亮
Looks good.
乔  能帮我拿下食物吗
Joe, will you help me with the food?
好
Yeah.
嗯
很抱歉我们来迟了
I'm sorry we're so late.
-堵车  -报价到了吗
- The traffic was - Did the number come in?
三百万
Three million.
不错啊
That's...pretty good.
我们没要
We passed.
这是令人鼓舞
I-It's, uh, encouraging
这么早就吸引了注意
to get the interest so early on, you know.
但我们想试试找风投
We're gonna try the VC route.
有几家公司在试探
A couple firms are poking around.
听着  你今晚还来睡吗
Hey, listen, are you still sleeping over tonight,
还是你还得送戈登回家
or do you have to take Gordon home now?
不  博斯送他回去
No, Bos is gonna drive him back.
那好
Okay.
-好吗  -好
- Okay? - Okay.
我怎么会错过在
I wouldn't miss my first night
莉迪娅和伦尼的蜜月婚床上度过的第一晚
in Lydia and Lenny's Honeymoon Hotbed.
嗯  好吧
Yeah, well...
他们似乎进展挺好
They seem to be doing all right.
好吧
Well...
今晚起
as of tonight,
我正式算对他们将信将疑了
I'm officially giving them the benefit of the doubt.
你怎么样了
So how you doin'?
流浪者进展不错
Well, Rover's comin' along.
另一件事呢
Yeah, and that other thing?
我很高兴地报告
Yeah, well, I'm happy to report
我在慢慢摆脱那个麻烦
I'm digging myself out of that particular hole.
或许实际上没有听着那么糟
Probably sounded a lot worse than it was.
戈登  我之前也没想那样为难你的
Gordon, I -- I didn't mean to come at you like that,
整件事让我很过意不去
and I feel shitty about the whole thing.
博斯  得了  没事的
Bos, Bos, come on. Don't sweat it.
我听说美国在线要
Well, I heard AOL is gonna --
提出收购
gonna make you an offer.
你会接受吗
Are you gonna take it?
你怎么听到的
Now, how did you hear about that?
卡梅
Cam.
是啊
Yeah, right.
他们给我们压了低价  三百万
Turns out they low-balled the hell out of us at three mil.
他们现在在到处买
They're in a buying frenzy right now.
我和乔想坚持下去
Me and Joe want to play this thing out, so...
嗯
Yeah.
你怎么突然变机车党了
So when did you go all Hells Angels on us?
得了  那是辆小本田
Come on. It was a baby Honda!
差不多是轻型摩托了
It was technically a dirt bike.
是太空摩托才对
More like a Space Bike.
"太空摩托"
"A Space Bike."
闭嘴啦
Shut up!
总之  我现在换了
Anyway, I don't have one anymore.
-开卡车了  -是啊  太空卡车
- I drive a truck now, so... - Yeah. A Space Truck.
-好吧  -太空卡车
- Okay. - Space Truck.
你们还想再喝点啤酒吗  再来点吧
You guys want another beer? Let's have one more.
不了  我们还有人得开车呢
No, some of us gotta drive.
-来嘛  戈登  你不开车吧  -那倒好了
- Come on. Gordon, you don't have to drive. - I wish...
-来嘛  -我累坏了
- Come on. - ...but I'm beat.
走吧  博斯
Shall we, Bos?
我们该走了
I think we gotta roll.
走吧
Come on.
-好吧  -见到你真好
- Well, all right... - This was good to see you, man.
见到你也很高兴
Good to see you, too.
嗯
Yeah.
我送你
Yeah, I'll walk you out.
好
Okay.
那好  戈登
All right, Gordon.
-谢谢你送我了  -嗯  回见
- Thanks for the lift out. - Yeah, yeah. I'll see you soon.
-谢谢你过来  -不客气
- Well, thanks for coming by. - Sure. Yep. Yep.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
-谢谢帮我挂灯  -嗯
- Thanks for the help with the lights! - Yeah.
乔
Joe?
这位叫谭雅的姑娘
This girl here, this Tanya,
可比姓哈丁的那个好多了
much nicer than that Harding girl.
我的名字永远被一个
My name has been forever sullied
谭雅·哈丁和南希·克里根
皆为花样滑冰选手
94年1月的全美花滑锦标赛前
克里根被人打伤腿  只得退赛
而哈丁得了冠军
但两人皆入选冬奥会
媒体开始大肆报道
克里根的受伤
以及此事可能跟哈丁
和其男友杰夫·古利有关
叫"古利"的男人抹黑了
by a man named "Gillooly."
我们有点冒险精神吧  好吗
Hey, let's get a little adventurous, shall we?
试试海胆
Um...let's try some uni?
-好  -好
- Yes. - Yes.
我想跟你谈谈西塞尔
I wanted to talk to you about Cecil.
他在整页方面还是有困难
He's still having trouble with whole pages.
他都做了一个月了
He's had a month.
或许他不是合适的人
Maybe he's not the guy.
想摆脱他可不容易
Well, it's gonna be a little hard to get rid of him.
他可是团队的创建成员
He's a founding member of the team,
还是首席技术官
CTO and all.
新来的在帮忙做苦工了
So the new kid's helping out with the grunt work,
但西塞尔还是应对不来编程的挑战
but Cecil still can't handle the programming challenge.
-慢用  -来
- Enjoy. - Here.
你一定得尝尝这个
You're gonna want to try this, dude.
嗯
Yeah.
这是传统日本灵魂食物
This is some old Japanese soul food.
你会喜欢的
You're gonna like this.
我也有事想问你
I wanted to ask you about something, too.
我听说美国在线对搜索有兴趣
Um, I heard that AOL is interested in a search play.
或许能摆脱这团麻烦
It might be a way outta this whole mess.
听着  我第一个承认
Look, I-I'll be the first to admit
我根本看不懂代码
that I don't know the ins and the outs of the code.
但在买卖公司方面
But when it comes to buying and selling companies,
那可以说是我的专长
you could say that's my bailiwick.
你觉得我们能卖多少
How much do you think we could get?
我的消息是三百万以上
My man says upwards of three million.
好吧  我们得偿还天使投资人
Okay, we have to pay off the angel investors --
那也不赖
Yeah, we'll do all right.
每人能拿到40万
We'll do all right, about 400K apiece.
但团队
But the team --
他们能分到近一百万现金
They split almost $1 million in cash.
这对一群新人来说很不错了
Now that's pretty good for a bunch of young upstarts.
-但他们有三个人  -我知道
- But there's three of them. - No, I know.
-这主意  我真觉得不...  -听着
- This idea -- I really just don't think - It's -- Look, it's --
这总归不是个小数目
i-it's still nothing to sneeze at.
对你是个胜利
Hell, it's a win for you,
让你能很好地迎接下一个项目
it sets you up great for your next thing.
再说  遗憾的是
Besides, the sad truth is,
所有用我们的网站搜索的人都不是很满意
anyone done a search with us leaves underwhelmed.
流浪者搜索量第一的词条是"性"
The top search on Rover is "sex."
第二是"彗星"
The second most popular search...is "Comet."
流浪者搜索量第一的词条是"性"
The most popular word being searched on Rover is "sex."
第二是"彗星"
The second most popular word is "Comet."
你明天应该会接到一通电话
You should get a call in the next day.
报价大概会是三百万
Expect the offer to be around $3 million.
博斯是代表你们两个人吗
Can I assume that Bos speaks for the both of you?
博斯  你在销售方面很有经验
Bos, you have a lot of wisdom when it comes to sales.
但我们不能现在出局
But we can't get out now.
我们有可能获得成功
We have a winning play here.
我们以算法为基础的系统有六个模仿网站
Our algorithm-based system has a half dozen copycats.
但彗星没有  为什么
Comet doesn't. Why?
因为据预计  到年底网络会扩大一倍
Because web growth is projected to double by the end of this year,
到95年底就能达到三倍
triple by the close of '95.
正是因为有竞争对手才应该退出
The competition is exactly the reason to get out now.
我们没有合适的程序
We don't have the right damn programmer --
是你说  我们不"小打小闹"
You said we don't make "small plays."
我们"出手要大"
We take "big swings."
我的直觉告诉我
What I know, in my gut,
搜索能成为
is that search is poised
价值上亿的行业
to be a billion-dollar business.
我不管你在高尔夫球场上遇到了谁
I don't care who you run into on the golf course,
你不能跟我之外的人讨论我的资产
you don't discuss my assets with anyone but me.
如果需要给流浪者换领导才能取胜
If the path to victory requires a change in the Rover leadership,
那我们可以讨论
we can discuss that.
但现在  有点勇气
But, in the meantime, have some grit.
我叫你们统一了阵线再进来
I told you to come in here and present a united front.
不要跑来跟老板抱怨
Don't come whining to the boss.
这是最常见的扯淡
This is 101 bullshit.
你们都得拿出更好的表现
Do better. Both of you.
你们走出去时
And when you walk out that door,
要往同一个方向走
I want to see you head in the same damn direction.
谢谢你刚刚支持我
Well, thanks for having my back in there.
你欠第一国家银行32.6万
You owe $326,000 to First National Bank.
我从11月就知道了
I've known since November.
你在复印室里打印银行文件
You've been running off bank paperwork in the copy room
就像把那儿当成自己家似的
like it's your home office.
-你有张单子落下了  -等等的
- You missed a sheet. - Hey, wait a minute --
听着  我明白你想干什么
Hey, listen, I see what you're up to.
你想把流浪者丢给第一个出现的买家
You want to unload Rover to the first buyer
好让你自己赶紧捞一笔
so you can get a quick windfall.
-但你  -长远的计划  首轮融资
- Oh, but you -- The long-game, Series A --
是帮不了你的
that won't solve your problem.
这事我可没说出去
I haven't breathed a word about this.
我也不会说的
And I'm not going to.
因为我会支持你
Because I have your back.
真希望你也支持了我们
I just wish you had ours.
兄弟们  找到一个
Dudes, got one!
说真的
Seriously, guys,
格兰德威尔-布里斯托尔最合适了
Gladwell, Bristol is the perfect fit.
-找到一个  -我们好棒
- Got one! - Yay, us!
怎么回事
What is up?
是我们的每周网站索引比赛
It's our weekly website indexing contest,
截止周五  索引最多网站的队伍获胜
the team with the most sites by the end of Friday wins.
-快点  -还有2分钟
- Go, go, go! - 2-minute warning.
-接近吗  -不相上下  海莉也加入了
- We're close? - Neck and neck. Haley's in the mix.
我们过去吧  走
We should get down there. Come on.
我们以前按话题分组
So we used to cluster the groups by topic,
但我们的首席本体论专家认为
but our Chief Ontologist found that
分享信息能提高生产力
it boosted productivity to share info,
所以她把团队分成了七大组
so she's put the teams into seven master groups.
-找到一个  -好诶
- Got one! - Aooga!!
好诶
All right!
很好  他们追上来了
All right, they're inching up.
加油  窈窕奶爸  你们知道这多重要
Come on, Mrs. Doubtfire, you know what's at stake.
像1989年那样研究网络
Research the web like it's 1989!
-找到一个  -我们好棒
- I got one! - Yay us!
很好  加油  燃烧组
Yes! Step it up, burners.
让方达骄傲
Make Fonda proud.
兄弟们  找到一个
Dudes, got one!
来吧  燃烧组
Oh, it is on, burners!
他们似乎很有冲劲  大奖是什么
They seem pretty fired up. What's the grand prize?
-金牌吗  -比那还好
- Olympic Gold? - Better.
好了  时间不多了
Okay, we don't have much time.
就要到了
We're almost there.
胜负就要分出来了
We almost find out who the victor is.
我们好棒
Yay, us!
好接近啊
It is so close.
-找到一个  -好诶
- Got one! - Aooga!!
加油  好了  马上了
Go! Oh! Okay, we're there!
加油  加油
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
我刚登记了一个萝茜·奥唐纳的网站
I just logged a Rosie O'Donnell site!
好诶
All right!
等等  不不  放我下来
Wait. No. No, no, no. Put me down.
好了  冲浪板
All right. Surfboard!
好啊  冲浪板
Yay! Surfboard!
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
爸爸  过来
Hey, Dad -- Hey, Dad -- come over here!
你确定不是该你了吗
Are you sure it's not your turn?
绝对不是
Definitely not.
好吧
All right.
好啊
All right!
准备好了吗
You ready?
好了  冷静点
All right, calm down!
关掉啊
Turn off!
该死
Goddamn.
你干什么
What are you doing?
滑冰要开始了
Skating is coming on.
谭雅和南希  整个美国都在看
It's Tonya and Nancy, and all of America is watching,
我想看看结果如何
so I want to see what happens.
我在看《真实世界》
I was watching "Real World,"
这一集里大卫会被赶走
and it's the episode where David gets kicked off
-因为扯塔米的床单  -谁在乎啊
- for pulling the sheets off of Tami-- - Oh, my God. Who cares?
-那才不是真的  -姑娘们  别吵
- It's not even "Real." - Girls, can you please?
我在网上读到说
I read something online
那些闹剧都是他们有意编排的
that said they generate all the drama.
就像你
Kind of like you.
那是什么
What is that?
金滑板
It's a golden surfboard.
为什么会在你这儿
Yeah, why do you have that?
亲爱的  那是哪来的
Honey, where did you get that?
是彗星的
Well, it's from Comet.
我知道拿个彗星的奖杯回来很奇怪
And I know it's weird to have a Comet trophy
毕竟你在为流浪者忙里忙外
when you're working so hard on Rover --
不会
No.
上面为什么写着"锅贴"
Why does it say "Potstickers"?
因为我赢了
Because I won it!
瑞莎当时在为红花餐厅网站写简介
Risa was doing a write-up for the Benihana website,
我就跟她说我喜欢锅贴
and I told her that I love potstickers
她就把我们队起名叫锅贴  今天我们赢了
so she named our team Potstickers, and today we won.
我们干翻了燃烧激情
And we kicked Feel the Burn's ass!
大家都欢呼了  他们放了超赞的冲浪音乐
And everyone cheered, and they played this crazy surfer music,
我还冲爸爸的脸上扔了庆祝派
and I got to throw the ceremonial pie in Dad's face!
什么
What?!
是啊  可赞了
I know! It was amazing!
好吧  南希要热身了
Okay, Nancy's about to warm up.
你是我姐姐  我知道你内心深处
You're my sister, and I know deep in your heart
是想观看这个重大的文化事件  并吃冰淇淋的
you want to watch this major cultural event and eat ice cream
-而不只是抽恶心的烟  -闭嘴
- and not just smoke disgusting cigarettes... - Shut up!
对大家拉着个脸
...and scowl at everyone.
-来吧  妈妈  来  -好吧
- Come on. Mom, come on. - Okay.
没有什么能阻拦她
And nothing is going to hold her back.
那好吧
Well, all right. Okay.
真希望我有机会冲爸爸脸上丢派
I-I wish I got to throw a pie in Dad's face.
我也想
Yeah, you and me both.
-厉害  -好啊
- Ooh, sassy. - All right.
-我错过了什么  -加油  南希
- What'd I miss? - Go, Nancy.
你觉得他们速度有多快
How fast do you think they're going?
-你看得到吗  -嗯
- Hey, can you see okay? - Yeah.
我能很好地看到你耳朵后面的奶油痂
I've got a perfect view of the crust of Cool Whip behind your ear.
什么
What?
来
Here.
我擦吧  没事的
I got it. I got it. Don't worry about it.
-谁能比她更好  -是很好
- Who is gonna top that? - It's good.
这下我更紧张了
Now I'm even more nervous.
我不知道你打算回家
I didn't know you were coming home.
要一起来吗
You wanna join us?
第一跳是三转空翻
Now this first jump is a triple flip.
我得去洗个澡
I got to take a shower.
再见
Bye.
知道吗  她是个斗士
You know what? She's a fighter.
就我的了解  她会为每一个动作使出全力
If I know her, she's gonna fight for every triple from here on out.
怎么回事
Hey, what happened?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我
I...
回头再告诉你吧
I'll tell you later.
我不是有意闯进来的
I didn't mean to barge in.
没有
No, not at all. I, um...
我想给你介绍大家
I wanted to introduce you to everyone.
我们需要人打破平局
Hey, we need a tie-breaker.
你站南希还是谭雅
Are you Team Nancy or Team Tonya?
那是滑冰选手吗
Are those skater people?
我要去睡了
I'm just gonna go to bed.
才过去三分钟
Into the program only three minutes.
现在要进入最难的三...
Now going into the hardest triple --
勾手三周
a triple lutz.
下次你听到滴水声
You know, the next time you hear a drip...
该死
Damn it!
最好温柔点操作
...you might want to try a gentler approach.
对了  我知道这看上去什么样
I know how this looks, by the way.
就好像我提前经历了可悲的中年危机
Like I'm having some pathetic, early mid-life crisis.
机车  卡车  拖车
Got the bike, the truck, the trailer.
不不  恰恰相反
No. No, on the contrary.
其实  你冒了险
Actually, no, you took a risk,
你脱离了自己的"安全区"
you got out of your "comfort zone."
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
得了
Right.
我的新家陷在泥巴里了
My new home got stuck in the mud.
是啊  最好的人也难免遇到这种事
Yeah, well, happens to the best of us.
偶尔拜托人帮忙没什么可耻的
There's no shame in asking for a little help now and again.
你怎么会知道怎么做这些的
How do you know how to do all this anyway?
你家族有住拖车的历史吗
You come from a long line of trailer folk?
其实  也差不多
Well, truly, that ain't far off.
给  这个你留着
Here. Why don't you keep this.
没准哪天又用上了
You never know when it's gonna come in handy.
要喝点什么吗
You want a drink?
不了
Nope.
我不喝了
I'm good.
但你可以去我车上
But you could run out to my truck
我的工具包在座位上
and, on the seat, there's my tool bag.
把管道工的腻子给我拿来
Grab me the plumber's putty out of there.
-一个小油罐  -好
- Little can. - Okay.
谢谢
Thanks.
我要把你的指甲锉弄脏了
I'm dirtying up your nail file...
还是刷子
...or brush thing...
什么的
or whatever you...
我没找到
I couldn't find it.
你的船怎么样了
Hey, how's your boat?
我把能变卖的都卖了
Well, I liquidated whatever I could,
还把养老金全取了出来
zeroed out my IRA.
我本打算卖家具的
I was ready to auction off all the furniture.
但是
But I thought --
又怕黛安发现
well, I thought Diane might notice
她的古董餐具架不见了
if her antique buffet turned up missing.
可以解决的
It could work out.
流浪者或许能成功呢
Rover might succeed.
不  我几个月前看过
No, I looked at it a couple months ago,
虽然还不成型
it wasn't there yet.
但我喜欢那个模型
But I liked the model.
我们的程序员
Our programmer's been
几个月来一直挠破头
banging his head against the wall for months
想改进算法
trying to refine that algorithm.
唐娜又不肯卖
And Donna won't sell it.
我看得出迹象
I recognize the signs,
这个项目不行的
this thing is gonna die on the vine.
我是说
I mean...
我们完了
We're screwed.
我们完蛋透了
We're so screwed,
完蛋的光
the light from screwed
要几千年才能照到我们
gonna take a thousand years to reach us.
等等  你有多完蛋
Wait, how screwed are you?
我们没有好领导
We don't got the leadership,
没有好算法
we don't got that algorithm,
也没有人才
and we don't got that talent.
也就是说  亲爱的
In a word, darlin',
我们没有你
we don't got you.
他卡在哪里了
What part is he stuck on?
我就是说  凯蒂·赫曼博士
I'm just saying, Dr. Katie Herman
对你颇为本体论地关注
gives you a lot of ontological attention.
嗯  她挺友好的
Yeah. She's friendly.
很好  重摆
Nice scratch.
她对我可没那么友好
She's not friendly with me.
是啊
Yeah, well,
你和卡梅伦·豪伊博士怎么样了
how are things with you and Dr. Cameron Howe?
那辆清风房车挺舒服的吧
Must be pretty snug out there in that Airstream.
就像两个住在顶针里的巨人
Like two giants living in a thimble.
就差一点
So close.
尝试可嘉
Excellent try.
挺好  她...
So, it's -- it's good. She's, um...
她想寻找什么
She's looking for something,
我觉得她在无人区是找不到的
and I don't think she's gonna find it in no man's land.
但是
But, um....
我过意不去  因为她很喜欢  但是
I feel bad, because she's so into it, but...
我很讨厌那地方
...I hate it out there.
我总忍不住去想磕头虫
And I can't stop thinking about click beetles.
磕头虫是什么
What's a click beetle?
你还自称喜欢户外活动呢
You call yourself an outdoorsman.
你在荒野里
So, you're in the wild,
能听到一种滴答响
and you hear this clicking sound.
你以为自己要疯了
And you think you're going crazy
或是突然爆发耳鸣了
or have sudden onset tinnitus,
但事实上  是你的耳蜗里进了种
but in fact, there's an ear-dwelling beetle
钻耳朵的虫子
in your cochlea --
真的  你会死的
I'm serious -- and you turn up dead.
那只虫子就在你脑袋边
With a beetle next to your head.
因为  它爬出来了
Because, you know, it crawls out.
就在你死后
When you die.
乔  那是《星际迷航2》里的
Joe, that was in "Star Trek II."
-没看过  -你看过的
- Never seen it. - Yes, you have.
磕头虫是真的
And click beetles are real.
-好棒  -厉害
- Yes! - Nice!
虽然没瞄那个的  但也算
Wasn't aiming for that one, but it counts.
你觉得格兰德威尔-布里斯托尔
So what do you think of Gladwell, Bristol
厉害的风投公司怎么样
and their smokin' VC operation?
我本来对美国在线的收购提议很期待的
Well, you know, I was excited about the AOL offer.
但后来又不感兴趣了
Until I wasn't.
然后我又对风投方案充满期待
And then I was excited about the VC route.
但又不感兴趣了
Until I wasn't, so...
你究竟期待什么
What are you... really excited about?
这个
This.
你和我
You and me.
这里
Here.
好吧
Okay...
如果你进了这一球
If you make this shot,
我们就拿风投的钱
we're taking the VC money.
好
Fine.
-我们不拿他们的钱  -好  再摆上
- We're not taking the money. - Okay, okay. Rack 'em.
开始吧
Here we go.
好了
Okay, okay.
那么
So...
你们都知道
So, uh, as you all know,
我们起初有些不顺利
we got off to kind of a rocky start --
但上个月  你们突然实现了大逆转
but last month, suddenly, you really turned it around.
真是太棒了
Just...
功劳属于西塞尔
Credit goes to Cecil
在算法上获得了突破
for his breakthrough with the algorithm.
-恭喜  -西塞尔
- Yay! - Cecil!
我们很骄傲
We are so proud
给你们提供首轮融资
to offer you Series A financing.
敬流浪者
To Rover.
To Rover!
-干得好  -谢谢
- Good job. - Thank you.
唐娜
Donna.
我欠你个道歉
I owe you an apology.
我起初没看出来  但这个真的很厉害
I didn't see it at first, but this thing is killer.
你的人干得太棒了
I mean, your guy nailed it.
-是啊  是这样  -嗯
- Yeah. He really did. - Yeah.
敬坚持
To perseverance.
恭喜
Congratulations.
感觉很棒吧
Well, that must feel really good.
我知道这个很不容易
Look, I know it's been a tough one,
考虑到我们一个月以前的处境
and given where we were a month ago,
肯定觉得像一发曲线球吧
it must feel like a curve ball.
但会有收获的  等着看吧
But it will pay off, you'll see.
你真的办成了
You really pulled this off.
而且正及时
And just in the nick.
一个月前
About a month ago,
唐娜本打算把它们卖给美国在线的
Donna was gonna dump the whole thing to AOL.
-我们都很高兴  -是啊
- It's been good for all of us. - Oh, I agree.
你们认识吗
Oh, you know each other, right?
你把局面完全打开了
So you really cracked the whole thing wide open.
怎么做到的
How'd you do it?
其实点子是博斯出的
Bos actually had the initial idea,
我们称之为"等候室"概念
what we call the, uh, the "waiting room" concept --
嗯  人们经常等待
Yeah, people wait around all the time,
他们都习惯了
they're used to it.
现实生活中也是  网上也是
In -- In real life. On the web.
我想出了个"排队程序"
I, uh, came up with a "queuing program."
我们是第一个索引整个网页的网站
Now we're the first site to, uh, index entire pages.
我们有个网络爬虫
You know, um, we had a crawler,
但很原始
but it was a rude one...
是啊  我们得好好调教它一下
Sure, we had to teach that little sucker some manners.
打扰
Excuse me.
我就是想感谢你没放弃我们
I just wanted to thank you. For not giving up on us.
你稳住了大局
You steered the ship.
你该为自己骄傲
You should be proud of yourself.
你成了大明星啊
So, you're the star of the show.
是啊
Y-Yeah.
-发展喜人啊  -是啊
- The, uh -- the growth has been incredible. - Yeah.
我就是有点意外
Well, I was just a little bit surprised.
因为之前你困住了好久
Because, well, you know, you'd struggled for so long.
我得问一句
So I just -- I have to ask...
是谁写的新算法
Who wrote the new algorithm?
我无法相信
I cannot believe
流浪者得到了首轮融资
that Rover is getting a Series A term sheet.
现在  突然间
Now, all of a sudden,
我们要应付一个资本雄厚的噩梦了
we're up against this capitalized nightmare.
什么网络爬虫跟数据索引交互
Some new "crawler" interacting with the data indexing,
这能害死我们
it could kill us...
我们为竞争得分散精力
We've got to divide our focus just to compete.
但我们的方法  人工处理
But our whole approach, the human touch,
现在完全完...
it's -- it's now completely and totally f--